(267) 596 - 6677 vtjia51@gmail.com 810 Snyder Avenue Philadelphia, PA 19148

Vincent Tjia

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/vincent-tjia-5ab2751b8 | Github:

https://github.com/binnie51 Website: https://github.com/binnie51/portfolio3.0.git

Junior Software Engineer - Entry Level

A full-stack certified developer with a background in graphic design and art. Prompted to start my journey in tech a year ago after years of working with Amazon's internal data tools. In addition to art, I am also passionate about computer science, data, analytics, innovation, and learning new things. Able to learn new technologies as fast as learning a new foreign language. Along with my background in design, I am excited to apply these skills to creating a better experience on the web.

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS/Bootstrap/tailwind
- JavaScript
- JS libraries: Jquery, React, Node
- Express

- SQL
- MongoDB
- Java
- Python
- MS Excel, Word, PowerPoint
- Google Tools
- Foreign Languages

WORK EXPERIENCES

06/2019 - 03/2020

Fulfillment Associate, Amazon Logistics DPH2 - King of Prussia, PA

- Worked in the "Problem Solve" team to ensure quality products are sent to customers in a timely manner.
- Took on a leadership role while facilitating high morale.
- Registered faulty items and replaced them using Amazon's data tools.
- Mastered Amazon's internal tools for package management within a short period.
- Worked with workflow spreadsheets to track daily shipments.
- Fixed device issues such as scanners and printers.

03/2020 - 03/2021

Learning Ambassador, Amazon Logistics DPH2 - King of Prussia, PA

- Trained new hires and cross-trained associates in the "Problem Solve" team.
- Trained new managers in outbound "Problem Solve" processes.
- Promoted and facilitated Amazon's code of conduct to ensure safety.

- Assisted managers by participating in leadership meetings and helping on-the-ground workers when needed.
- Performed role audits, new-hires audits, and other audits associated with training and performance.
- Helped establish CampusShip onto the station.

03/2021 - 09/2021

Learning Ambassador, Amazon Logistics DDP2 - Philadelphia, PA

- Ran intro class for new-hires.
- Cross trained associates in "Problem Solve" procedures and other crucial roles on the pick-up driveway.
- Registered faulty items and replaced them using Amazon's internal data tools.
- Performed accuracy check on completed works.
- Read metrics and time-tracking to ensure daily operations are running smoothly.

PROJECTS

Movie Watchlist

> First group project. A front end app where users are able to create a personal watchlist of movies they wish to see. Databases are streamed from existing third-party APIs onto the client side, this case being: imDB and omDB. It will then display movies, descriptions and trailers based on the user's input. Users are able to save particular movies into the 'My Watchlist' page. This app uses Materialize as the css framework.

> Responsibilities:

- Breaking down group tasks by dates.
- Creating wireframes.
- Styling the pages.
- Populate the modal pop-up with data and added closing features.
- > Utilized: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Materialize css, IMDb & OMDb APIs.

Weather Dashboard

- ➤ An application that takes users' input of a city and enables users to view that particular city's weather forecast for up to 5 days. It relies on the third-party Weather API call to retrieve the weather data by making requests with specific parameters to a URL, as well as grabbing icons that reflect on the forecasts. It utilizes local storage to store previously searched cities in a JSON format and it will again present the users with forecast conditions for that city when clicked on. Users may delete their search history as well.
- > **Utilized:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap, and Weather API.

CodeOp

Another group project. CodeOp is a full-stack application where nonprofits with a lack of developer team could provide a space for real-world experiences through projects for both experienced and inexperienced developers to showcase their expertise. The site is built using the Model View Controller (MVC) architecture pattern as a way to separate different aspects of the application such as organizing both frontend and backend. Agile practices were also exercised throughout the development process.

> Responsibilities:

- Creating wireframes.
- Determine the page layout and color schemes.
- Designing logo and creating graphic images.
- Building Handlebars templates.

> Utilized:

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, and Bootstrap on the frontend.
- MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js and Node.js on the backend. Insomnia for testing.
- Express-session and cookies for authentication.
- Faker.js for generating fake contextual datas for testing and development.
- Google spreadsheets for organized project management tools.

EDUCATION

Graduated 05/2018 Associate of Arts: Art and Design, Community College of

Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA

Graduate 09/2022 Certificate for the completion of Coding Boot Camp,

University of Pennsylvania - Philadelphia, PA

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Indonesian Native

Japanese Upper-Advance Chinese Upper-Beginner